Inventory of the Robert William Hughes Papers 1818-1900
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Correspondence, 1818-1900, n.d. (Folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence, 1880-1889., 22 items. (Folder 2-3)
    - Benjamin Harris Brewster, Department of Justice, Washington, D.C., to R.W. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 20 March 1882., 1 page. TLS. (Folder 3)
      Received Hughes' letter regarding Judge L. Lewis for United States Attorney for the Norfolk District, and will give it due consideration.
    - John Paul, Harrisonburg, Virginia, to Judge [Robert W. Hughes?], n.p., 21 Nov. 1882., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Paul's election as judge is being contested and he will not withdraw under fire.
    - W[illia]m D. Shipman, New York, [New York], to Judge [Robert W.] Huges [sic], Norfolk, Virginia, 5 Dec. 1882., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Concerns Judge Hughes' decision in the Washington case, and Mr. Shipman's re-argument thereof.
    - E.G. Burks, Liberty, [Virginia], to R.W. Hughes, n.p., 22 January 1883., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Asks advice on the purchase of law books relating to federal practice.
    - E.B. Washburn, Ex-Minister to France, Chicago, Illinois, to R[obert] W. Hughes, n.p., 20 Nov. 1883., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Thanks Hughes for his letter about the Coles family, and praises Gov. Edward Coles for his work for the state of Illinois.
    - W[illia]m Butler, Eastern District of Penn[sylvania], Philad[elphi]a, [Pennsylvania], to Robert W. Hughes, [Norfolk, Virginia], 11 March 1884., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Concerning recommendation for admitting of Edward J. Fox into the Bar and his character and integrity.
    - Dan[iel] B. Lucas, Charlestown, W. Virginia, to Judge R.H. [sic] [W.] Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 27 April 1884., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Concerns publication of Lucas' address on John Randolph.
    - J.G. Armstrong, St. Philip's Rectory, Atlanta, Ga., to Judge [Robert W. Hughes] n.p., 9 Feb. 1886., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Regarding an ecclesiastical law case.
    - J.G. Armstrong, St. Philip's Rectory, Atlanta, Georgia, to Judge [Robert W. Hughes], n.p., 26 Feb. 1886., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 3)
    - Oden Bowie, Baltimore, [Maryland], to Judge [Robert W. Hughes], n.p., 21 March 1887., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Reply to letter concerning the death of a horse, Gabriel.
    - J[oseph] E. Johnston, Washington, D.C., to "Lizzy" [Eliza M. (Johnston) Hughes], 17 Sep[tembe]r 1887., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Has been busy preparing a report for the Secretary of the Interior. Hopes to visit them and see the growth "of the town of which I have heard much."
    - W[illiam] H[enry] F[itzhugh] Lee, House of Representatives, Washington, D.C., to R[obert] W. Hughes, Circuit Court, Richmond, [Virginia], 24 Oct. 1888., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Hughes' letter received concerning his [Lee's] absence from the caucus; as soon as election is over, will comply with his request.
    - Rough draft of an article written by R.W. Hughes on the history of certain Richmond newspapers, [ca. 1890]., 16 pages. ADf. (Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1890-1900., 6 items. (Folder 3)
    - M[elville] W[eston] Fuller, Washington, [D.C.], to R.W. Hughes, n.p., 2 April 1890., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Noticed that Hughes recently heard a case concerning the constitutionality of the Virginia Dressed Beef Law, and comments that he too will be handing down an opinion shortly involving a similar case from Minnesota, with Indiana also involved.
    - J[abez] L[amar] M[onroe] Curry, [Washington, D.C.], to R.W. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, 31 Jan. 1896., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Concerning Curry's inquiry and receipt of documents for use in an address; information regarding his relationship with Gen. [Joseph E.] Johnston; and duties during Mr. Buchanan's administration.
    - Jo[h]n W. Daniel, U.S. Senate, Washington, D.C., to R[obert] W. Hughes, n.p., 14 Dec. 1896., 2 pages. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Concerning expenses for a stenographer, silver and politics, and mention of McKinley.
    - A[lfred] M[agill] Randolph, Norfolk, Virginia, to Mrs. [Robert W.] Hughes, n.p., 27 January 1900., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Acknowledges receipt of a pair of socks knitted by Mrs. Hughes.
    - W.N. Armstrong, University Club, [New York], New York to Judge [Robert W.] Hughes, n.p., 29 M[arch] [l9]00., 3 pages. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Thanks Hughes for the manuscripts and papers concerning the [Civil War], and relates the feeling of his club as one of "much to learn on the great question which split North and South."
  - Correspondence, n.d., 7 items. (Folder 3)
    - J[ohn] M[oncure] Daniel, n.p., to "My dear Sir" [Robert W. Hughes?], n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Explains that he cannot give editorial support in elections.
    - D[avid] Davis, n.p. to Judge Ro[bert] W. Hughes, U.S. Court Room, Norfolk, Virginia, n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Received Hughes' letter of the 5th and comments on the date that the Judiciary Bill will be introduced to the Senate.
    - B[asil] W[ilson] Duke, n.p. to Col. Rob[ert] [W.] Hughes, n.p., n.d., 1 page. ANS. (Folder 3)
      Called to see but Hughes wasn't in; enclosed the pedigree of "Skidaddle," which he requested.
    - G[eorge] P[ayne] R[ainsford] James, n.p., to [R.W.] Hughes, n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Asks him to meet Dr. Mackay at four o'clock.
    - Certificate stating that Miss E[liza] M. Johnson [sic] [Johnston] contributed $1.00 to the erection of the Washington Monument, Washington, [D.C.], n.d., 1 page. PM. Drawing. (Folder 3)
      Contains drawing of proposed monument.
    - Card of invitation of Sir W[illia]m Gore and Lady Ouseley to Mr. and Mrs. [Robert W.] Hughes for dinner, n.d., 1 page. C. (Folder 3)
    - H[enry] H[oratio] Wells and Charles Whittlesey, n.p., to R.W. Hughes, n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Folder 3)
      Concerns an order furnished by Mr. Forbes in the case of Smith, a bankrupt, in United States District Court.
  Series 2
- Printed Material and Manuscript Volumes, 1829-1897., 20 items. (Folder 4)
  - Numerous articles about horses written by various people, printed in the American Turf Register and Sporting Magazine, 1829-1830., 9 items. PM. (Folder 4)
  - Editorial entitled "Judge Hughes' Letter" printed in the Valley Virginian, Staunton, Virginia, 16 January 1879., 1 item. N. (Folder 4)
    Discusses Robert W. Hughes' opinion of the constitutionality of the [Virginia] Funding Bill of 1871, which also had been published by the Valley Virginian[not included].
  - Article printed in the Turf, Field, and Farm, New York, New York, 4 February 1881., 1 item. N. (Folder 4)
    Discusses opinions expressed by Judge Robert W. Hughes to Maj. Thomas W. Doswell, 20 January 1881, about "Where to Breed the Thoroughbred Horse." Including 4 Cys of NC1s of the aforementioned letter printed in The State, Richmond, Virginia, 11 February 1881.
  - Opinion handed down by Judge Robert W. Hughes in the case of Faune vs. The Commissioners of the Sinking Fund of Virginia, discussing the state debt, August 1884., 1 item. NCl. (Folder 4)
    Printed in a Richmond newspaper.
  - Letter printed in the Richmond Dispatch, Richmond, Virginia, from Ro[bert] W. Hughes, n.p., to Dr. D.S. Watson, Louisa Co., Virginia, 23 April 1886., 2 items. 2 Cys of NCls. (Folder 4)
    Discusses Virginia as the home of the thoroughbred trotter.
  - Letter printed in the Richmond Dispatch, Richmond, Virginia, from Robert W. Hughes, Norfolk, Virginia, to Col. Saunders D. Bruce, n.p., 9 April 1887, giving Hughes' opinion about fast trotters coming from thoroughbreds, 10 April 1887., 2 items. 2 Cys of NCls. (Folder 4)
  - Printed text of Centennial Address delivered by Judge Robert W. Hughes to Franklin and Marshall College, Lancaster, Pennsylvania, entitled "Chief Justice Marshall and his Work," 14 June 1887., 2 items. 2 Cys of PV. (Folder 4)
  - Reprint of address delivered by Judge Robert W. Hughes before the Virginia Press Association entitled "Editors of the Past," 22 June 1897, in The Times, Richmond, Virginia, 27 June 1897., 1 item. NCl. (Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook No. 1 of Ro[bert] William Hughes, n.d. (Folder 4)
    Contains pamphlets and newspaper clippings of various articles by him, and articles that interested him. Also includes J.H. Platt, Jr., Secretary, Union Congressional Republican Executive Committee, Washington, D.C., to R.W. Hughes, Abingdon, Virginia, 17 Sept. 1870.